To protect my clan and friends,
为了守护战团和伙伴们
I must
我绝对…
conquer Keild Labyrinth.
会成功攻略凯路德迷宫的
Rud.
路德
Lily?
莉莉？
I have a favor to ask.
我有事想拜托你
Ow…
好痛
What's the big deal?
干吗突然把我拉进来啊？
Please help me with the straps on the back.
后面的绳子绑不起来 请帮我一下！
There, all done.
好了 绑好了
Thank you.
谢谢你
I see. I'll leave you to it then.
这样啊 那我回去了
Wait.
请稍等一下
There's something else I want to ask you.
我还有一点事想问你
Rud, you…
路德你 那个…
You'll do your best
今后会作为战团团长
as a clan leader, right?
努力经营战团 对吧？
Well, yes.
是啊 没错
You're amazing.
真厉害呢
I thought so when you made that declaration in front of everyone.
你在大家面前宣布
I can't even tell other people the things I want to do.
根本不敢告诉任何人自己想做什么
Is there something you want to do?
你有什么想做的事吗？
Promise you won't laugh?
你能保证不会取笑我吗？
Promise.
当然
I don't have any grand goals like you,
我不像你 有那么远大的目标
but I don't want to let myself rely on Lilia all the time.
只希望自己不要老是依赖姐姐
I want to be able to stand on my own.
我想变成可以独当一面的人
When I'm with Lilia,
只要在姐姐身边
I never have to worry about anything.
我就不用为生活苦恼
Growing up, I've always been clumsy. I always mess things up.
其实我从小就笨手笨脚
But Lilia would always be there for me.
但是姐姐总会在身边保护着我
Lilia is perfect
姐姐她真的很完美
and she can do anything.
而且很厉害 什么事都难不倒她
She's a fierce fighter.
战斗的时候也很勇猛
And I can only support her from the rear.
而我总是只能在后方支援她
Isn't that because you're good with magic?
那是因为你比较擅长魔法吧
Lilia can use magic too,
姐姐明明也可以用魔法
but she fights close combat.
她却选择近战攻击
And when we use Fusion,
而且融合时
Lilia always takes control.
总是由姐姐担任主人格操控身体
I've never fought on my own.
我从没有自己战斗过
I see.
原来是这样啊
I always wondered who took control
我确实一直很好奇
when you guys fused.
你们融合时都是谁在操控身体
But, I can't always depend on Lilia.
不过我不能总是这样仰赖姐姐
I want to stand on my own feet.
我想要独自完成自己想做的事
I see.
原来如此
That's why she approached me.
所以她才会突然跟我搭话啊
Given how close they are, it may be hard to tell her sister
她们姐妹俩的关系这么亲密
Lily, you can trouble me.
莉莉 你可以尽管给我添麻烦
Go ahead and go after what you want to do.
试着去做做看自己想做的事吧
Really?
真的可以吗？
Then I'll get your help the next time I want to do something…
那等我下次想做什么时
Lily?
莉莉？
I thought I heard Rud…
我好像听到了路德的声音
Lilia.
姐姐
-Rud… -It's not what it looks like, Lilia!
-路德 -不是的 莉莉亚！
You've got it all wrong! This is a misunderstanding!
你误会了 这是一场意外！
Can you come to the roof with me?
可以跟我来屋顶一趟吗？
Is she going to push me off the roof?
我会被推下去吗？
What are you afraid of?
你在怕什么啊？
Don't worry.
放心吧
I'd have thrown him off if it had been any other guy.
但今天如果不是你 我早就把对方推下去了
But you're not the kind of guy
因为路德不可能会出手伤害
That was just an act
刚才有一半是演技
to get you out here.
这都是为了把你带出来
Have I told you about our past?
我跟你说过我们的过去吗？
You said you were abandoned by your parents
你说你们被父母抛弃
and have been traveling on your own.
是靠互相扶持才走到现在的
Well, rather than say we were abandoned,
不
it would be more accurate to say we ran away because we were being abused,
正确来说其实是因为父母会虐待我们
mostly by our father.
尤其是父亲经常会虐待我们
So what happened earlier was a surprise.
因此就算刚才真是一场意外
You're one of the few guys she can communicate normally with.
你也是少数可以跟她正常交流的男生
That's why
正因如此
I wanted to talk to you.
我才想跟你聊聊
I want to take Lily
我希望有一天
to a place where she can be happy.
可以带莉莉去一个 能让她打从心里感到幸福的地方
Until then, no matter what happens,
在那之前无论发生什么事
I swear to protect her.
我都会誓死守护她
I see.
这样啊
You two are very considerate of each other.
你们两人都很为彼此着想呢
Lily told me
莉莉刚才告诉我
she thought you were perfect and amazing.
姐姐是个完美又厉害的人
I'm not as good as she thinks I am.
我根本没有她想得那么好
Right.
是啊
I don't think you're perfect either.
我也觉得你不是个完美的人
You lose your cool
该说只要牵扯到你妹妹
whenever your sister is involved,
你就会失去冷静
almost like you're a different person.
感觉像是变了一个人
I don't want to hear that from you.
我唯独不想被你这么说
Thanks for hearing me out.
谢谢你听我说这么多
You're my companion, after all. You can tell me if anything's bothering you.
毕竟你是我重要的伙伴啊
When's Lilia coming back?
姐姐还不回来吗？
Lilia, Lily, sorry to keep you waiting.
莉莉亚、莉莉
Not at all.
不会啦
We just came back from the 49th floor.
我们正好刚从第49层回来
The 49th floor?
第49层？
Yes.
是的
I had the investigator
我请迷宫调查员先带我去一次
so I could use my Dungeon Walk to take everyone there directly.
这样我就能用迷宫传送送大家过去了
You're a lifesaver, Lily.
帮大忙了 莉莉
Not at all.
这不算什么
Also,
顺带一提 之所以没有直接去第50层
was to assess the monsters' spawn rate.
是为了了解魔物的出现频率
I've gathered quite some intel on my end too.
我这边也收集到挺多情报的
First, the party composition of the two clans.
首先是两大战团 攻略迷宫时的队伍成员有谁
Black Dragon Fang uses
黑龙之牙那边
four attackers including the leader
包括队长在内有四位攻击手
and two healers to support them.
加上两位支援和辅助的补师
White Tiger Claw uses four magic attackers
白虎之爪则是四位魔法攻击手
and two healers.
加上两位补师
In other words, both clans focus primarily on speed.
也就是说这两支队伍都比较重视速度
That's why they have their attackers double as tanks.
所以才会让攻击手兼任肉盾的职责啊
Regardless of floor,
另外不论在哪一层
it seems there is a high risk of abnormal statuses.
都有许多会使用异常状态的魔物
In that case, we can use
这样的话 应该可以用我的技能
my Strong Body to nullify that.
“强健肉体”让异常状态无效化
This is going to be a challenging labyrinth,
虽然这个迷宫有些棘手
but no matter what, we will conquer the entire labyrinth
但我们无论如何都要突破到51层之后
and form an alliance with the two clans.
跟两大战团结盟才行
-All right.
-没错！
I'll take the lead.
那我负责打头阵
Marius will take the rear.
玛里乌斯殿后
Okay.
好
Luna will handle close combat.
露娜负责近战
Lilia, as usual, will move and act as she sees fit.
莉莉亚跟平时一样视情况自由行动
Nin will restore the shield force and issue commands…
妮恩负责回复护盾
Is something the matter, Lily?
怎么了吗？莉莉
Um,
那个…
can I be the one to give commands during battle?
战斗时 可以由我来发布指令吗？
Already trying to make a change?
这么快就想努力试着做出改变了啊
I understand.
我知道了
It might be easier for us if Lily could oversee the battle from the rear.
由后卫的莉莉 来发布指令反而会更好理解
Then Lily will be the main commander. Nin will support her.
那就以莉莉为主
Got it.
明白了
I'm counting on you, Lily.
那就拜托你了 莉莉
Sure.
好的
Okay, let's go.
那么要出发了
Dungeon Walk!
迷宫传送！
This space doesn't favor those who rely on speed in combat.
这空间对靠速度战斗的人不太有利呢
But it's perfect for a tank like me.
不过对我这个肉盾来说或许非常合适
The spawn location set for the monsters is around here.
设置魔物的地方就在这附近
It would seem so.
好像是这样
You can tell, too, Rud?
路德也分辨得出来吗？
Only vaguely, though.
是啊 虽然只是隐约感觉得到
That's because you're the manager of Avancia Labyrinth.
因为你是阿凡锡亚迷宫的管理者啊
They've set it up quite cleverly.
话说回来 对方配置得很巧妙呢
These two paths
这两条左右分开的道路
lead to the same place,
虽然最终抵达的地方都一样
but monsters will appear on both.
但两条路上都会出现魔物
Say, we take the left and encounter monsters,
比方说 如果我们在左边战斗
then the monsters from the right will also come at us from behind.
那右边的魔物就会从后方追过来
So, they're trying to trap us?
所以对方是想夹击我们吗？
Exactly.
正是如此
The guardian here
这里的守护者可能是个相当狡猾的人
It's the Poison Lizard!
是毒蜥蜴！
The Black Owl is coming from the right!
右边过来的魔物是黑鸮！
Sacrificial Shield!
牺牲之盾！
Taunt!
挑衅！
Poison gas?
是毒雾？
Sorry…
不好意思啊
but abnormal statuses won't work on me.
异常状态对我不管用
It defended with its magic?
它用魔力挡下攻击了吗？
More Black Owls!
又来了好几只黑鸮！
Rud,
路德 虽然我们应该能打败它们
but we shouldn't waste energy here.
但还是不要留在这边跟它们硬碰硬
You're right.
说得也是
You guys keep going.
你们先继续往前走
Leave it to me.
这里交给我就好
Got it.
是
Everyone, this way!
各位 往这里走
Flash magic stone!
闪光魔法石
Lily, your commands were on point.
你下达的指示很不错喔 莉莉
They were easy to understand.
真的非常容易理解呢
I'll continue to do my best.
休息后我也会全力以赴的
By the way, I just realized something.
话说我刚才发现一件事
Rud's Sacrificial Shield,
路德的牺牲之盾
I think we can decide whether to transfer the damage to you or not.
好像可以由我们决定 是否要将护盾耗损转到你身上
We couldn't do that before.
之前明明没办法自己决定
Your skill level must have gone up
难道是和我战斗过
after you fought me!
技能就强化了吗？
Maybe…
或许是吧
It's all thanks to me!
那就是我的功劳吧
That means we can disable the damage absorption
这样不想让路德背负伤害时
whenever we want.
就可以自己解除技能了呢
But Rud's skills are certainly something.
不过路德的能力很异常呢
It's rare to see a tank
能完美引开魔物的肉盾可不常见喔
That's true.
确实如此
I used to think all tanks could do that.
我还以为肉盾基本上都做得到
Rud's just on a completely different level.
其实是路德实在太厉害了
Even if you say that…
就算你们这么夸我…
It'd be great
如果路德之后 也能用自我回复的技能就好了
That sounds like another difficult thing.
你又突然提出那么困难的要求
Does such a skill even exist?
真的有那种技能吗？
What? So humans don't know about this?
什么啊？人类不知道吗？
"Humans"?
“人类”？
Are you not one yourself?
难道你不是人类吗？
Um, not entirely?
这个嘛 应该不完全是吧
Incidentally,
这么说起来 我们确实不太清楚你的事呢
That's true.
是啊
We risked our lives to fight you last time,
虽说曾经赌上性命跟你拼死一战
but now you're not giving off any malicious intent, so…
但现在完全没有危险的气息
It completely slipped our minds.
所以就忘记问你了
Marius, if you don't mind, would you tell us more about yourself?
玛里乌斯 方便的话 可以跟我们说说你的事吗？
Only what you're comfortable with, of course.
当然只要说你能说的部分就好
I was worried whether or not you guys would accept me.
我不确定你们是否能接受我的身份 所以感到很不安
Actually…
其实…
I am a demigod.
我是魔人
A demigod?
魔人？
Yes.
没错
Broadly speaking,
我们所处的世界
the world consists of humans and demihumans.
大致上可以分为人族和亚人族
It is said that in the past, there were even demigods.
据说在更早之前还有魔人族
Demigods and demihumans do not differ much in appearance,
魔人和亚人在外观上并无差异
but those who worship the devil instead of god are called demigods.
但他们不像人类般敬仰神明
That's the gist of it.
简单来说是这样
I can oversee the labyrinth because I am a demigod.
正因为是魔人 所以才能管理迷宫
What does that mean?
这是什么意思？
You didn't know?
你们不知道吗？
It may seem as if humans are benefitting from labyrinths,
虽然现在看来 人类是在利用迷宫谋取好处
but labyrinths were created
但迷宫其实啊
by the devil to destroy the human world in the first place.
是魔神为了 摧毁人类世界才创造出来的
What?
什么？
So, labyrinths weren't created by god to enrich our lives?
迷宫不是神明为了让人类
Where did you get that from?
那种说法是从哪里来的啊？
Well, it's like a folklore.
这算是传说吧
Indeed.
是啊
There might have been those who knew the truth in the past.
或许以前真的有人知晓这些事实
Anyway, that's the story.
总之事情就是这样
So, this labyrinth must be guarded by a demigod too,
因此这个迷宫 肯定也是交给某个魔人管理
and a strong one at that.
而且还是个相当厉害的强者
So, you better be careful when you challenge the guardian.
所以跟守护者对战时 还是小心一点比较好
We get that,
我明白了
but wouldn't that make them kind of like your brethren?
不过魔人对你来说应该就像同胞吧？
Are you okay with that?
这样没问题吗？
I hate those guys.
我讨厌那些家伙
Since I live like this,
如果要以这种方式活下去
I want to defeat them as Marius, not as a demigod.
那我不想当一个魔人
I see…
这样啊
Sorry.
抱歉
I had my own motives
我其实是为了自己的战斗
for coming to this labyrinth with you guys.
才跟你们一起来攻略这个迷宫
Well,
至少在我心中 你算是我的伙伴
So, I'm counting on you.
所以今后也拜托你了
I have no objections as long as you don't hurt Lily.
只要不会危害到莉莉 我就没有任何意见
I'll pretend I heard nothing.
刚才那些话 我也会当作没听到的
Same here.
我也是
We're friends as long as you don't hurt Lilia.
只要你不会伤害姐姐就是我们的伙伴
I expected that.
你们老是那样说
All right. I'm in too.
不过我也同意
Me too.
我也是
Aren't you glad?
太好了
I owe it all to you.
这都是多亏了你
Thanks, Rud.
谢谢你 路德
Um…
那个…
Lily?
莉莉？
Sorry to ruin the mood,
抱歉在气氛正好的时候打扰各位
but I'd like to discuss the strategy
我想跟大家讨论一下
to deal with the monsters on the 50th floor.
该如何与第50层会出现的魔物战斗
Of course. I'll leave it to you.
好 那就拜托你了
Yes.
好的
First, the lizard.
首先是蜥蜴人
I think we should play it safe…
我认为应该保守一点…
We fought off the monsters
后来我们几个
as they appeared and progressed.
一边击退出现的魔物 一边向前迈进
Finally, we reached the 50th floor.
总算抵达第50层
There it is! The Bone Dragon!
出现了 是骸骨龙！
Let's do this!
各位 要上了！
Taunt!
挑衅！
Taunt was effective.
挑衅的效果很好
We should be able to proceed according to Lily's plan.
应该可以照着莉莉拟定的计划行动
According to the information about the Bone Dragon,
根据第50层会出现的魔物
which appears on the 50th floor,
骸骨龙的情报看来
it will frequently use abnormal status skills.
它应该会频繁使出异常状态技能
That may disrupt our formation,
这可能会使我们的阵形遭到破坏
so Rud will go in and block it first.
所以路德先过去挡住它
The rest of the party should stay out of its range.
其他成员不要进到它的攻击范围内
Understood.
知道了
Lilia and Marius will attack from outside its range.
姐姐和玛里乌斯 从它的攻击范围外进行攻击
It's a bone monster,
因为它是骸骨魔物
so it's better to attack it by smashing it rather than cutting it.
别用砍的 用击碎的方式攻击 效果应该比较好
Got it.
-我知道了 -好
Also, it's weak to fire.
另外它的弱点是火属性
We should enchant our weapons with fire before attacking it.
我认为该先将武器 附加火属性再进行攻击
We should use mainly fire magic too.
魔法也以火魔法为主
its body will…
它的身体就会…
Rud!
路德！
Thanks, Lily.
-谢谢你 莉莉 -不会
Taking cover under its wing is a no-go.
不可以躲在翅膀正下方
I'll have to be cautious before I make my move too.
移动前再稍微吸引一下他的注意力吧
Master!
主人！
It's okay, Luna.
别担心 露娜
He let it hit him to put distance between them.
他是刻意以那种方式被弹开 借此拉开距离
It is faster than I expected.
它的动作比我想象中还快
And this puts me too far from my party.
而且这样跟大家离得太远了
Thanks, you two.
谢谢你们两位
No problem. I've been trying to get pumped up.
我正想大闹一场呢
Good. Let's keep this up.
-很好 以这股气势打倒它吧 -好
Its attacks are fast and powerful,
虽然它的每一击又快又沉
but as long as we watch closely and be careful, we should be fine.
但只要看清楚 做好防守应该就没有问题
What's going on?
怎么回事？
A ranged attack?
范围攻击？
Are you guys all right?
你们没事吧？
It was a slight wound,
虽然只是稍微擦伤
but I seem to have been poisoned.
但我好像陷入毒系的异常状态了
Same.
我也是
Nin, heal them while I distract it.
妮恩
Got it.
知道了
Luna, heal them with me.
跟我一起帮他们治疗 露娜
Yes.
是
Take this!
吃我这招！
Taunt!
挑衅！
What? That thing…
什么？这家伙…
It ignores Taunt when it is continuously attacked
如果一直遭受攻击
I think my shoulder is dislocating…
肩膀好像快脱臼了！
My shield feels so heavy.
盾变得好重
What's with this stuff?
这些泥是怎么回事？
Someone cast water magic!
谁来帮我施个水魔法！
It's stuck and I can't--
泥土紧黏着 完全甩不下来
This stuff is weighing down my shield…
因为这些泥土 盾牌变得太重了
Rud!
路德！
Thanks for that, Nin.
谢啦 妮恩
This is turning into a battle of endurance.
不过这下似乎要变成长期战了呢
In that case…
这样的话…
What's that?
那是什么？
An automatic recovery area.
那是自动回复区
It's a saint skill that only Nin can use.
只有妮恩可以使用 是圣女技能之一
You can treat abrasions there.
站在那里就能治疗护盾
All set up.
我设置好了
Make the most of it.
记得好好利用喔
Got it.
好
ONE HOUR LATER
（一个小时后）
This thing is still going…
这家伙还不倒下吗？
What?
怎么回事？
This is the thing Lily mentioned…
这是莉莉说过的…
Its flame is coming!
炎要来了！
Everyone, take cover!
大家快躲开！
Rud?
路德？
-Rud! -Master!
-路德！ -主人！
Why are you surprised?
在惊讶些什么啊？
You think you can burn me to a crisp with that?
以为我会就这样被烧成木炭吗？
The successive attacks have depleted 5,000 shield force.
因为被连续攻击
This is not looking good.
这下不太妙
You're in it now.
你刚才让我吃足苦头呢
I'll kill you as you wish.
就让我来干掉你吧
Now!
趁现在！
It's working.
效果很好
Just a little more!
再一下下 肯定就能打败它
Taunt!
挑衅！
Thank you, Rud!
路德 谢谢你！
This is just…
对我们来说 这里…
a stepping stone for us!
只是一个过渡点！
Life Conversion!
生命转换！
It's the Bone Dragon's drop.
是骸骨龙的素材
Finally, it's over…
终于结束了
Congratulations on breaking through the 50th floor.
恭喜你突破第50层
Thanks.
谢谢
But,
不过呢
I don't think we're in any shape to continue further.
这种状况下
Yeah.
是啊 今天就到此为止吧
Rud,
路德
I think we should hold off selling the loot we got today for now.
关于今天得到的素材
Otherwise, news of our raid might get out.
攻略顺利的消息 传出去对我们也不太好
You have a point.
你说得对
Then we'll sell them another time.
那就改天再一起卖吧
Lily, your instructions after returning are perfect too.
莉莉
Um…
那个…
I'll do my best for the next floor too.
到了下一层 我也会加油的
Now, as customary, let's celebrate!
那就依照惯例 去庆功一下吧
Yes!
好的
I'll pass.
抱歉 今天我就不去了
I'm a little tired.
因为有点累
I want to rest early.
所以我想早点回去休息
I'll head back too.
那我也回去了
See you tomorrow, everyone.
各位 明天见